杰森:这是本的,这是开萝尔的,这是麦琪的,这是麦琪的,
Jason: This is Ben's, this is Carol's, this is Maggie's, this is Maggie's,
这也是麦琪的,这真是有趣,本,你今天过得如何?
this is Maggie's, this is fun!Oh, hi, Ben.How was your day?
本:还行.
Ben: I've had better!
这是:怎么了?
Jason: Yeah, what happened?
本:汉德尔太太在课间的时候把我叫到她办公室,就我好斗的性格教育了我.
Ben: Mrs.Handel called me in during recess and reamed me for being truculent.
杰森:你知道好斗的含义吗?
Jason: Do you know truculent means?
本:不知道,但应该是不好的
Ben: No but it can't be good.
杰森:好斗意味着生气和准备打架.
Jason: Truculent means angry, ready to fight.
本:哦,这也太严重了吧!
Ben: Oh, and there I thought it was serious.
杰森:是很严重,本.
Jason: That is serious, Ben.
麦琪:嘿!大家好!
Maggie: Hi guys!
杰森:嘿!
Jason: Hi.
麦琪:我生活中最喜欢的人现在怎么样呢?
Maggie: How is the favorite man in my life?
本:很好.
Ben: Fine.
杰森:我也很好.
Jason: I am fine too.
麦琪:哦,你得洗衣服了!
Maggie: Oh, you did the laundry!
杰森:是的,可以少洗一个人的衣服.
Jason: Yeah, in-between saving the sanity of half-a-dozen people.
麦琪:放松,坐下然后放松,
Maggie: Well, you relax and sit down and relax,
我会先给你做一下按摩,
I will give you one of my famous back rubs,
然后我再去做晚饭.(传呼机响起)
and then I will make dinner.(Pager Beeps) Uh-oh.
杰森:哦,你知道传呼机会响的,不是吗?
Jason: Oh, you knew that was going to be beep, didn't you?
麦琪:是的,但这并不意味着我必须去什么地方,
Maggie: No and it doesn't mean that I have to go anywhere;
只是我得马上给报社打电话.
it just means that I have to call the newsroom.
本和杰森:好的.
Ben and Jason: Right.
麦琪:喂,是的,我是麦琪·马龙,你传呼我什么事?
Maggie: Hello, yes, this is Maggie Malone, you beeped me?
杰森:麦琪,记得我有一次传呼你吗?
Jason: There was a time, Maggie, when only I beeped you.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:我是说有一次我传呼你.
Jason: I said there was a time when only ....
麦琪:嘘!是的,马上,我会马上去那边见员工.
Maggie: Hush......yes, yes, right away; I will meet the crew there.
本:该做晚饭了.
Ben: There goes dinner.
麦琪:德文伊中学出了点事,来了六辆警车.
Maggie: There is a big disturbance at Dewy High, they sent six police cars.
杰森:迈克在哪里?
Jason: Where is Mike?
麦琪:喂?开萝尔?你在哪里?什么?
Maggie: Hello?Carol?Where are you?What?
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:呃?开萝尔,我听不见?
Maggie: Er....?I can't hear ....Carol ....Carol?
杰森:开萝尔?
Jason: Carol?
麦琪:那是开萝尔,
Maggie: That was Carol, she was calling from Dewy High.
她是从德文伊中学打来的.她没有时间解释,
She didn't have time to explain,
她说她和迈克马上要被逮捕了.
but she said that she and Mike were about to be arrested.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
本:看来迈克和开萝尔是非常好斗.
Ben: Sounds like Mike and Carol are being mighty truculent.
学生们:不,我们不会走的!不,我们不会走的!
Students: Heck no, we won't go!Heck no, we won't go!
德尔斯:好吧,你们听着,你们正在犯一个大错!
Dearth: All right people, you are all making a big mistake!
我威利斯·德尔斯是不会被你们的示威所吓倒的.你呢?迪斯太尔.
Willis Dearth will not be intimidated by rabble.Do you mind Distil?
麦琪:哦,你看看这些孩子们!
Maggie: Oh, will you look at all these kids!
杰森:这是在闹事!
Jason: It's a sit in!
德尔斯:你们马上停止,这是你们最后的机会,防暴警察就要来了.
Dearth: This is your last chance; the police are on their way.
麦琪:亲爱的,这样下去会出大事的.
Maggie: Honey, this is going to get ugly.
杰森:这场面令我想起我的学生时代,你难道不是吗?
Jason: Brings back those good old days, doesn't it?
麦琪:开萝尔在那!
Maggie: There's Carol.
摄影师:麦琪?
Cameraman: Maggie?
麦琪:嘿!鲍比,这是我的丈夫.
Maggie: Hi Bobby, this is my husband.
摄影师:你好,马龙先生.
Cameraman: Hello, Mr.Malone.
这是:不不!实际上我叫……
Jason: No, no, actually I'm ...
摄影师:这真是太刺激了,不是吗?
Cameraman: This is great, isn't it?
这是:不,我们不能去,是的,这真是刺激!
Jason: Heck no, we won't go.Well it's catchy.
摄影师:谣言说今天闹事的领头叫迈克·西沃.
Cameraman: The rumor is that the real leader of this is some kid named Mike Seaver.
麦琪:不!
Maggie: No!
摄影师:唉,马龙夫人你认识他吗?
Cameraman: Yeah, you know him Mrs.Malone?
麦琪:不,我们并不……
Maggie: No, we never...
杰森:我们应该……
Jason: Well we should...
摄影师:那好,我们去找他.
Cameraman: Well, let's find him.
麦琪:不不!
Maggie: No, no, your camera might intimidate him.
你的摄影机会吓倒他的,还是让我去找他吧!
You should just let me find this kid,
现在还不确定谁是真正的领头闹事者.
who probably it's really involved at all.
摄影师:好的,那我先去拍些准备抓学生的防暴警察们.
Cameraman: ok, I'm going to go shoot some B roll of the cops getting into their riot gear.
杰森:嘿!迈克.
Jason: Hey......Mike.
迈克:嘿!爸爸妈妈,你们在这里干什么?
Mike: Hey, mom and Dad, what you are guys doing here?
麦琪:这个问题我们可以在回家的路上谈.
Maggie: We can discuss that in the car on the way home.
迈克:当时我们现在正在做爸爸以前在大学里做过的事.
Mike: But we are just doing what dad did when he went to college.
斯塔伯恩:西沃医生,越南战争真的是你一手结束的吗?
Stabone: Doctor Seavor, Is it true that you single-handedly ended the Vietnam War?
杰森:一手结束是有点夸张了,但是我……
Jason: Oh, single-handedly would be a bit of an exaggeration.But I did....
麦琪:开萝尔?我希望你能比迈克理智一点.
Maggie: Carol?I expected you to have more sense.
开萝尔:妈妈,这样的事业值得任何的牺牲.
Carol: Mom, when the cause is just the cost is worth any sacrifices.
麦琪:好吧,这件事不值得你去牺牲.
Maggie: Well, this cause isn't worth the sacrifice.
杰森:但你还不知道是什么事业.
Jason: Yeah, you haven't even heard the cause.
迈克:是的!
Mike: Yeah!
麦琪:杰森,我们待会再谈这是什么事业,
Maggie: Jason, can we discuss this later,
现在防暴警察已经来了.
there are police getting into riot gear.
迈克:对不起,妈妈,我哪里也不去.
Mike: I'm sorry, mom, but I won't go anywhere.
麦琪:迈克,我真是很难想到平时只会为了年轻女孩才努力的你,
Maggie: Mike, I found it hard to believe that you've developed a commitment
今天能有什么事让你这样为之努力?
to anything beyond teenage girls.
斯塔伯恩:这真是让我大吃一惊呀!
Stabone: I was pretty shocked myself.
迈克:妈妈,你能不能先听听这里到底发生了什么?
Mike: Mom, would you please just listen for a minute about what's going on here?
这是:是的,麦琪,我们先坐下.
Jason: Well, Maggie, sit down
麦琪:好吧,我宁愿蹲下也不愿坐着.
Maggie: Ok, I'll squat, but I won't sit.
迈克:好吧,这一切开始于两天前罗维特教练的课上.
Mike: Ok, it all started two days ago in Coach Lovett's class.
教练:出现这问题的原因是什么?为什么人们会抛弃一切而驾着马车向西部挺进?我再说一遍,
Coach: Which leads to this question,
为什么人们会抛弃一切而驾着马车向西部挺进?斯塔伯恩,你回答.
why did these people give up everything and head
west in covered wagons?
Let me repeat that, why did these people give up everything
and head west in covered wagons?Stabone
斯塔伯恩:因为要是他们朝东走他们会掉进海里.
Stabone: Because if they head east they would have drowned.
教练:斯塔伯恩,要是我再叫你回答问题,你就来打我,好吗?
Coach: Stabone, if I ever call on you again just shoot me, ok?
斯塔伯恩:好的.
Stabone: Ok.
教练:好了,我们谈论的是我们的先驱驾着马车去开发西部的事,
Coach: Come on people, we are talking about pioneers, heading west,
那谁知道他们这么做的目的吗?
and wagon trains, why did they do it?
迈克:当时人们向西发展的原因很多:有的人是想闯事业,
Mike: Well they headed west for many reasons,
有的人是想去发财,
some wanted the chances to start over; some wanted to make their fortunes;
有的甚至为了逃避法律.
and some were even running from the law.
不过有一点是相同的,
What was common to all of them however,
那就是无论有多大的危险,
was the unyielding drive to follow a dream,
他们都坚定不移地追求梦想.
even if that promise took them into danger and over the distant horizon.
麦琪:你想让我们相信你?
Maggie: You expect us to believe that?
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
杰森:看来我最好也是蹲着吧!
Jason: It's better I squat too.
开萝尔:迈克只是讲了这件事的一部分.
Carol: Mike just get to the part of the story that matters.
迈克:好吧,那我们还是讲在课堂上……
Mike: Ok, all right.So there we all were in class.....
教练:等等,
Coach: Ok.Hold it people.
各位记得明天把学习总结交上来,
Now remember people, your term reports are due tomorrow and it should
但一定要用打字机打出来,
be typed on a typewriter.
You know the machine where you put the paper in it and it goes
现在下课,
Unless of course you have an IBM ...
但有两个男生留一下,
ok class dismissed, unless your last name ends in "S".
就是西沃和斯塔伯恩.
That's right, I'm talking to you Seaver and Stabone.
迈克:可教练我们没做什么错事呀?
Mike: But coach we didn't even do anything.
教练:那是因为你俩昨天的作业没做,所以留你俩在这里将昨天本应完成的二十道题做完.
Coach: Including your homework and that's why both of you dim bulbs are
going to sit here for as long as it takes to answer these 20 questions
you were suppose to answer last night.
迈克:但是,教练,
Mike: But coach, how were we supposed to answer these questions if we
我们连书都没有看过,你叫我们怎么做题目?
haven't even read the book?
斯塔伯恩:他以为我们是笨蛋.
Stabone: He thinks we are dim.
教练:这是答题卡,上面可以用钢笔,
Coach: Here are the answer sheets; feel free to answer in pen,
铅笔或颜色笔写.我现在去找德威特校长,
pencil or crayon.I have to go down to see Dewitt,
半小时后回来,到时希望你们写出了答案.
I will be back in about a half an hour,
给我安安静静地坐着!斯塔伯恩.
I expect to see something on those papers.No body fluids, Stabone.
斯塔伯恩:迈克,我们完了.
Stabone: Mike, we are dead.
迈克:不不!还没有呢!不是有句话说"有志者,事竟成"吗?
Mike: No, no, no, not necessarily.Where there is a will, there is a way.
斯塔伯恩:你是在说笑吗?你瞧这,
Stabone: Are you kidding?
讨论多纳党的形成和其历史意义.
Look at this, discuss the Donner party, what happened, and it's significance?
我甚至都没有听过,这叫我怎么答题?
I don't even know who's invited!
迈克:伯恩,第三排那个戴胸垫的女生是谁?
Mike: Bone, who is the girl in the third row with the falsies?
斯塔伯恩:是苏姗·哈里斯.
Stabone: Susan Harris.
迈克:不,另一个.
Mike: No, the other one.
斯塔伯恩:马洛尼·德文尼安.
Stabone: Maloney Devonian.
迈克:不不!另一个.
Mike: No, no, the other one.
斯塔伯恩:查洛·德拉诺?
Stabone: Chloe Delano?
迈克:是的,就是她,她不是每次都得A的?
Mike: Yeah, that's the one.She always gets straight A's.
斯塔伯恩:迈克,你是想抄袭她的作业?
Stabone: Mike, are you thinking about cheating off of her?
迈克:不,这方法我试过了,是行不通的,哇!你看这是什么?
Mike: No, I thought of it already.Wow, what do we have here?
斯塔伯恩:什么?
Stabone: What?
迈克:这像是洛维特教练的简历.
Mike: It looks like coach Lovett's resume.
斯塔伯恩:怎样?
Stabone: So?
迈克:上面说他已经三十八岁了,
Mike: It says here that he is 38 years old.
我原以为他的年龄会更大一些.
I thought he was a lot older then that.
斯塔伯恩:可能这是他孩子的简历.
Stabone: Maybe it's his kid's resume.
迈克:我想他也像我妈妈一样隐藏了他的实际年龄.哦,
Mike: I think he lies about his age just like my mom does.
你看这个,
Oh, look at this, it says the coach is married,
上面将洛维特先生已经结婚,你能想象一下洛维特教练老婆的样子吗?
can you picture coach Lovett with a wife?
斯塔伯恩:不行.
Stabone: No.
迈克:我原以为他是单身一人住在某个房子里,独自一人看看电视,
Mike: I always imagined him living alone in a room somewhere,
喝喝啤酒和发发牢骚.
watching TV while he drink beers and belched.
斯塔伯恩:我也是这样认为他的.
Stabone: That's how I pictured him.
迈克:谁会愿意嫁给洛维特教练.
Mike: Who would want to marry coach Lovett?
女生:打扰一下.
Girl: Excuse me.
迈克:你好!
Mike: Hello!
辛迪:洛维特教练在这吗?
Cindy: Is coach Lovett here?
迈克:不不!他刚好出去了,
Mike: No, no, he just stepped out for a second;
是去擦亮他的脑袋去了.
he went out to polish his head.
辛迪:我回家后会告诉他的.
Cindy: I'll tell him that when I get home.
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
辛迪:他是我爸爸.
Cindy: He is my Dad.
迈克:哦,天啊,天啊!
Mike: Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy.
斯塔伯恩:你们家是不是还有人像你一样?
Stabone: So are there any more at home like you?
温迪:嘿!西德尼,爸爸在哪?
Wendy: Hey Sidney, where is Dad?
迈克:哦,天啊,天啊!
Mike: Oh boy, oh boy, oh boy!
温迪:我简直不敢相信我有机会……
Wendy: I don't believe I have had the pleasure...
辛迪:你们是不是知道我们的父亲在哪?
Cindy: Do either of you know where our father is?
斯塔伯恩:他上天堂了.
Stabone: He arth in heaven.
迈克:他刚才说有事去校长室了,
Mike: He said something about going to the principal's office and look,
我为刚才说的话向你道歉.
I am really, really sorry for what I said .....
辛迪:别担心,我不会真的告诉他说你讲他出去擦亮他的头了.
Cindy: Don't worry, I won't really tell him you said he was out polishing his head.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Good.
辛迪:可是我记得你好像说过这句话的,开玩笑的了,你吓到了吗?
Cindy: That is what you said.I don't want to misquote you.Got you.
温迪:那么……
Wendy: So.....
辛迪:他对温迪不干兴趣.
Cindy: He is not interested Wendy.
温迪:辛迪,你怎么能说那样的话?
Wendy: Cindy, how could you say that?
迈克:你能不能相信洛维特居然有这样的女儿呢?
Mike: Can you believe Lovett has daughters like that?
斯塔伯恩:在他们老了的时候,他们就会脱顶的.
Stabone: Too bad when they get older, they could lose their hair.
迈克:虽然我认识他好多年了,
Mike: I mean, I feel that after all this time,
但还是对他不太了解.每天他离开学校以后,
I even didn't know him at all.
也有自己的生活,
After he walks out of this building he actually has his own life.
他都做些什么?他住在哪?
I mean what does he do?
他是不是还有其他很多漂亮的女儿呢?
Where does he live and does he have any more daughters that look like that?
斯塔伯恩:这是不可能的.
Stabone: It is not possible .
迈克:你难道对洛维特不干兴趣?
Mike: I mean, aren't you curious about Lovett.
要不要先去看看他是不在家?
Wouldn't you like to check him out?
斯塔伯恩:好的,但我们没有他的地址.
Stabone: Yeah, but we don't have his address
迈克:当然有办法,我们可以从他的简历中找出来.哦,他的地址是个邮箱地址.
Mike: Sure we do, we have his resume.Oh, his address is a PO Box.
斯塔伯恩:哦,我想住在邮箱里应该很不错的.
Stabone: Oh, if I lived in a box I'd be PO'ed too.
迈克:麦克吉尔夫人!
Mike: Mrs.McGill!
麦克吉尔:迈克!你已经好久没有到校长办公室了.
McGill: Mike!You haven't been to the principal's office in a long time.
迈克:麦克吉尔小姐,现在我们有个问题,
Mike: Miss McGill, we've got a problem.Mr.
塔特奇奥先生又不正常了,他把他自己藏在桌子下不出来了.
Datechio in detention, he is hiding under his desk again.
麦克吉尔:我们最好再去把他拉出来.
McGill: I had better go drag him out again.
老师:先生,你看看这些事还有没有解决的可能?
The coach: Do you think, sir, there is any chance for these things to turn around, sir?
校长:哦,看来这种机会小得就像你当上教育部长一样.
The principal: Oh, about as much chance as me being coming secretary of education.
教练:那么说就是没有希望了,我不是存心冒犯,我实在是……
Coach: So it's hopeless.I don't that.No offence, it was just ......
迈克:所以我们,我和波纳就去调查洛维特教练得私人生活.然后我们到了他家外面,一看他家,那也不是什么别墅,而是公寓楼,并且那些公寓楼差得简直就是贫民窟
Mike: So we, Boner and I, were are off to find out about coach Lovett's
secret life.We ended up outside his house.Over in JFK, only it wasn't a
house, it was an apartment, and it looked like the kind of place where Cagney
and Lacy pulled out their guns pretended they are men
斯塔伯恩:现在我们该怎么做?
Stabone: So what do we do?
迈克:好吧,我们进去看看!
Mike: Well, we look.
斯塔伯恩:行了,我想回去了.
Stabone: Ok.I'm ready to go.
迈克:来吧!我们到处随便看看.小心!是洛维特!
Mike: Well, come on, lets look around, come on.It's Lovett!
斯塔伯恩:我们差点被抓住!
Stabone: We are going to get caught!
迈克:我们不会被抓起来的!
Mike: We are not going to get caught!
斯塔伯恩:为什么抓起来?
Stabone: Caught doing what?
我们只是这样抱着躺在汽车里.
We are just a couple of guys cuddling on the floor of a parked car.
迈克:1,2,3,4,5,6,7!
Mike: One, two, three, four, five, six, seven!
斯塔伯恩:他是个天主教徒,你要干吗?
Stabone: He is Catholic.We are you doing?
迈克:猜猜!
Mike : Guess!
斯塔伯恩:迈克,你知道我们这样从窗户外偷看是会被抓起来的.
Stabone: Mike, you know we can get arrested for peeking in windows.
迈克:我们这不是偷看,我们只是看一下他们家的防火梯是否完好?我们可不想洛维特家的女孩们又什么不测,我们是这样想的,对吧?好的,是在二楼,来吧!
Mike: We are not going to peek; we are just going to check their fire escape to make sure that they are safe.We don't want anything happed to those
Lovett girls, do we?Ok, the second floor.Come on
斯塔伯恩:是的,也不是很高.
Stabone: Yes, its probably two flights up.
迈克:就是这里.
Mike: This is it.
斯塔伯恩:他讲话的确是唾沫横飞!
Stabone: He does belch!
教练:你可不可以告诉你妈妈为了身体健康就不要抽烟了吗?
Coach: Would you ask your mother to please control her bodily functions?
妻子:格拉汉姆,可那是她唯一的嗜好.
Wife: Graham, it's the only hobby she has.
女孩:妈妈,你有没有把牙医的话告诉爸爸?
Girl: Mom, did you tell dad what the orthodontist said?
教练:是的,我知道了!但是1600美元实在太多了.
Coach: Yes, she did, and 1,600 dollars is just way too much money.
女孩:但是爸爸,我要……
Girl: But dad, I need.......
母亲:我们以后再谈吧.
Mother: We can talk about it later.
女孩:要是不给我卖胸罩,那我就去做尼姑.
Girl: If I don't get braces, I might as well become a nun.
教练:那是一个好主意,我知道尼姑都有一副漂亮的牙齿.
Coach: That's a good idea.I heard nuns have a very nice dental plan.
女孩:爸爸.
Girl: Dad.
教练:好吧,我想每个人都给我回房做作业,
Coach: All right, I want everybody in their rooms doing their homework;
我和你们妈妈还有很多事要谈.
mother and I have some things that we need to talk about.
女孩:但是爸爸?
Girl: But Daddy?
教练:快点,大家全都快进去.
Coach: Hut, hut, hut..Everybody.
母亲:那么亲爱的,你已经和德威特先生谈过了?
Mother: So honey, did you talk to Mr.Dewitt?
教练:是的,我和那老流氓讲过了.
Coach: Yeah, I talked to that Pea Brained twit.
母亲:你是不是像我预计的那样说服了他.你瞧,
Mother: And you changed his mind just like I said you would.
亲爱的,我不是说过没什么浩担心的.
See honey, I told you there was nothing to worry about.
教练:我说得没起如何作用!
Coach: I changed nothing, nada, zip zero.
那个混蛋根本不听我的,所以这学期一结束,
The little gofer didn't even listen to me.
我还是要被解聘.
So as of the end of this semester, I am fired.
母亲:哦,格拉汉姆,那我们该怎么办?
Mother: Oh Graham, what are we going to do?
教练:嘿,嘿!你不用这个样子吧!
Coach: Hey, hey, hey, get that look off your face.
母亲:什么样子?
Mother: What look?
教练:就像你上次怀孕时一样的神情.
Coach: You know, the same look you had when you found out you were pregnant again this last time.
斯塔伯恩:迈克,我们离开这里吧!
Stabone: Mike, let's get out of here.
迈克:好吧.
Mike: Yeah.
教练:我们无需这么担心,你不是说已经把我的简历寄出去了?
Coach: We've got nothing to worry about.You said my resume is out right?
母亲:是的,今天还寄了二十份.
Mother: Yeah, twenty more today.
教练:那好的,你能想象得到像我一样的既有经验又有能力的教练居然会找不到工作?
Coach: Now, ok.You'd think that an educator with my experience and qualification will be snapped up.
母亲:哦,格拉汉姆,你说的对极了!我想原先寄出的五十份简历看来都是让邮局弄丢了.
Mother: Oh Graham, you are absolutely right.I'm sure those first fifty just got lost in the mail
斯塔伯恩:迈克,我想我们真的得离开了.
Stabone: Mike, I thought we were leaving.
迈克:好吧,好吧!我们走吧!
Mike : Yeah, yeah.We are.
教练:伊丽莎白,你把房间稍微整理一下,
Coach: Elizabeth put those pot-pies on hold for a for a while,
我要到外面吸一下新鲜空气.
I am going to step outside to get a fresh air.
母亲:好的.
Mother: ok
教练:我现在要怎么做呢?我现在到底要怎么做呢?
Coach: What am I going to do?What the hell am I going to do?
迈克:我真是难以相信我刚看到的一切.起先我以为他在出汗,
Mike: I couldn't believe what I was seeing.
因为他挺容易出汗的,
At first I thought he just must be sweating because the coach's sweats
后来我仔细一看,他是在哭.
in a snow storm.But the more I looked I saw that he was crying.
杰森:嘿!这事多久了?迈克.
Jason: Hey, long day, Mike?
迈克:我本想告诉你们的,
Mike: I wanted to tell you guys but I don't know how to tell you what
但我不知怎么告诉你们我所看到的一切,
I found out without telling you how I found out.
所以我就假装什么也没有看到,
I didn't know what to do so I just acted cool,
也就没有把这事告诉你了.
so you guys wouldn't notice anything weird.
杰森:不过今晚你是有点怪异.
Jason: You're acting kind of weird tonight.
迈克:哦,爸爸,
Mike: Oh, dad, good to see you too,
能见到你实在是太好了.要是你没其他事,我想上楼做作业.
if you guys will excuse me I have to go upstairs and do some homework.
开萝尔:一开始我就发现事情不妙,因为当时迈克看到我做操也没讲一句话,要是平时他总会取笑,所以我就知道事情的确挺严重的.
Carol; Oh this is where I come into the story,
I knew that something really serious was on mike's mind when he caught
me exercising and didn't make one of his cracks.
Well, you know like quick,
somebody push her back into the ocean or she will die.
迈克:开萝尔,我想和你谈谈.
Mike: Carol I need to talk to you.
开萝尔:为什么?
Carol: why?Then Mike told me everything he had seen and heard,
然后迈克告诉了我一切,
I had never seen him like this.
我从没见他如此认真过,这次他确实是想帮助别人.
He was actually thinking about someone other than himself,
出乎意外的是他请教我,
and if that weren't enough he asked me,
要知道他可是从来不会问我问题的,
me the person who he never listens too,
他问我怎样才能帮教练留住工作.
what he could do to save the coach's job.
迈克:开萝尔,你看,
Mike: Carol, look, this guy has really given me a lot and I just want
那教练真的帮了我好多,现在我只是想回报他一下.
a chance to give him something back.
开萝尔:好了,迈克,你又在想些什么整人的事?
Carol: Ok, Mike, what's your angle here?
迈克:开萝尔,这次我是认真的.
Mike: Carol I am serious.
开萝尔:你是认真的?
Carol: You?
迈克:是的,开萝尔,我该怎么做呢?
Mike: Yes.Carol, what can I do to stop this?
开萝尔:我也不知道.
Carol: Boy, I don't know.
迈克:要是你是我,你会怎么做?
Mike: What would you do if you were me?
开萝尔:要是我的话,我就会马上祈求上帝保佑.
Carol: Well the first thing I would do is to find a good skin doctor.
我是绝对不会让这么好的机会溜掉的.
Oh no, I am sorry, I couldn't let that opportunity pass.
迈克:那你能不能试试?我是说你看早上我过来看到你在做操,
Mike: Could you just try?
我有没有那样?
I mean, when I came here, you were exercising, did you see me go.....?
开萝尔:我想唯一的解决办法就是让德威特先生知道很多学生的想法和迈克一样,
Carol: The only solution that I could see was to show Mr.
要是这还不能说服他的话,
Dewitt that many students felt the same way as Mike,
那么我们得想办法吓一吓他.
or if it didn't convince Dewitt, at least it would frighten him.
所以第二天我,
So the next day, Boner, Mike and I spread the word,
迈克和波纳就在全校征收了三百个学生请愿签名.
and got 300 signatures on the petition.
麦克吉尔:好吧,现在他只想见你们的其中一个.
McGill: Ok he will see one of you now.
迈克:哦,祝你好运,开萝尔.
Mike: Oh, good luck.Carol
开萝尔:不不!这可是你发起这件事的.
Carol: No, no, no.You started this whole thing.
斯塔伯恩:好了,我倒是想去和德威特先生谈谈我的看法.
Stabone: Well I would like to give Mr.Dewitt a piece of my mind.
开萝尔:看来你没办法了,去吧,迈克!
Carol: You, you can't afford it.Go, Mike.
迈克:好的,但他向来不喜欢我.
Mike: Yeah, but he hates me.
开萝尔:不,他没有不喜欢你.
Carol: No he doesn't.
麦克吉尔:是的,他喜欢你.
McGill: Yes he does.
开萝尔:好了,会没事的,只是你到时说话的时候要尊重一点.
Carol: Well it will be ok, just work on keeping the contempt out of your voice.
麦克吉尔:你先练练,这很容易的,上帝,我真是喜欢我的工作.
McGill: With a little practice, it's easy.God I love my job.
校长:坐下,年轻人,有什么要我帮忙的吗?
The principal: Sit, how can I help be of help young man ?
迈克,是的,我是……
Mike: Well, I am....
校长:你是西沃!
The principal: Seaver!
迈克:你好,先生.
Mike: Hi, sir.
校长:好吧,
The principal: Well I don't know which one of your teachers sent you in
我不知道你是哪个老师派你到这里来的,现在要和一个惹事的学生谈谈,
here but I have a meeting with a concerned student right now,
所以你在外面等等.
so you'll just have to wait outside.
迈克:我就是那个惹事的学生?先生.
Mike: I am that concerned student sir.
校长:艾斯特拉,等我和西沃谈完了,
The principal: Estelle, as soon as I'm done with Seaver I want to see
你来见我.
you in here.
TDQ:快点.
TDQ: Make it quick.
迈克:好吧,
Mike: Well you see,
我们已经知道这个学期结束后,
some of us found out that coach Lubbock is going to be fired at the end
你就要解雇卢布克教练.
of this semester.
校长:并不是那样的.
The principal: Not true.
迈克:不是那样?
Mike: It's not?
校长:不是的,我们只是没有和他需签合同,那是我们现在资金短缺,
The principal: No, his contract simply isn't being renewed,
我对这个损失深表遗憾.另外,谢谢你能来和我谈话.
because there is a shortage of
funds.It's a tragic loss, I'm sick about it.Thank you for coming in
迈克:先生,
Mike: Excuse me for asking sir,
我能不能问问你这做法和解雇有区别吗?
but what's the difference between that and being fired.
校长:有很多区别,一方面……,
The principal: Plenty you see, on the one hand there is ....
另一方面……,不过这件事跟你又有什么关系?
and on the other hand of course you have...what is this to you anyway, Seaver?
西沃,你是不是又想搞些什么鬼?
What 's your angle here?
迈克:我没有搞鬼,我爱这教练,
Mike: No angle, I like the coach and I don't want to see him go.
所以我不想他离开.并不是我一人这么想的,外面还有至少三百个学生也是这样想的.
I am not the only one; over 300 other kids signed this.
校长:这就是我们教会学生写作的下场.
The principal: Why do we teach children how to write?
迈克:洛维特老师是个好教练,他挺关心人的.
Mike: Coach Lovett is a good teacher, he cares.
校长:关心人那可不是他的工作,他的工作是赢得足球比赛.
The principal: But he is not paid to care; he is paid to win football games.
一般来说这话我是不在学生面前讲的,
Now, ordinarily I wouldn't say that in front of a student,
但你也不太像个学生.所以我就……
but then you aren't much a student, so...
迈克:你这种做法似乎根本没有考虑过我们学生的意见.
Mike: You know it's almost like you are saying that our opinion doesn't
even count.
校长:不,我没有说似乎,
The principal: No, that's not almost like what I am saying,
我是说肯定.
that's what I am saying.
迈克:但是你不能……
Mike: But you can't....
校长:你看看,西沃,
The principal: Look Seaver, don't try to play mind games on Willy Dewitt.
别跟我玩脑筋游戏,你不会有什么好下场的.
You don't have what it takes.
迈克:你连脑子都没有,叫我怎么跟你玩脑筋游戏?
Mike: How can I play mind games on you when you don't even have a mind?(
(看来形势被我弄得挺紧张的)
Ok that point, I probably went a teensy bit too far).
迈克:那么看来我们得做些其他什么的,我们就静坐示威.
Mike: So we had to do something and this sitting in all that we...
开萝尔:开萝尔!
Carol: Carol!
迈克:这是开萝尔想到的.
Mike: Carol could think of.
杰森:迈克,我现在不知该说什么.
Jason: Mike I don't know what to say.
麦琪:我也是,我简直不敢相信你居然这样和你的校长讲话.
Maggie: Me either, I cannot believe you talked to your principal that way.
杰森:麦琪,他只是在坚持他认为正确的事.
Jason: Maggie, he's just standing for something he believes in.
麦琪:要是他现在站起来,我们也就不会有问题了.
Maggie: Well, if he would just stand up now, we wouldn't have a problem.
迈克:妈妈,你看看你周围的人群,
Mike: Mom, just take a look around you,
整个学校的学生都在支持洛维特教练.
I mean the whole school is buying Coach Lovett.
警察:这是非法集会,
The police: This is an unlawful assembly,
你们要是不马上解散就会被逮捕的.
you will all disperse immediately or you will be arrested.
迈克:嘿!你们要去哪里?波纳,你能相信这吗?
Mike: Hey, where are you going?Can you believe this, Boner?
波纳:我也得走了,我可不想被逮捕.
Boner: I have got to go Mike; I am not allowed to get arrested.
摄影师:现场的镜头还不到一分钟,没有暴力,
Cameraman: We are going live in less then a minute and there is no violence,
没有流血,这只是街边的芝麻小事!
there is no blood and there is no gore.This is news it's sesame street.
迈克:好吧,大家再等会,
Mike: All right, hold on everybody,
这正是考验我们的时刻,我们不怕被逮捕,
look there is a lot more at stake here then just being arrested and getting
不怕抛头颅,撒热血,其他我不想讲太多的了,
our heads bashed in with blood and guts...well we don't need to dwell on that.
不管怎样,我都要留在这里帮助鲁布克教练.
But I am here to save Coach Lovett and I am staying
波纳:你要留下?
Boner: You are?
迈克:是的!
Mike: I are!
校长:看来这又是你的一个记录了,西沃先生!
The Principal: This is going on your record, Mr.Seaver.
开萝尔:我也留下.
Carol: I am staying too.
斯塔伯恩:我也留下,我是说在牢里家人就打不到我.
Stabone: Me too, I mean my folks can't punish me if I'm in jail .
麦琪:迈克 ,开萝尔,
Maggie: Mike, Carol, please lets go,
我们走吧!他们说要把你们抓起来,你没去惹恼警察干吗?
they are talking about having you arrested.Please, why bother the policemen?
迈克:对不起,妈妈,我既然参与了这件事,我就得坚持到底.
Mike: I am sorry mom, but I am in this thing and I am staying.
开萝尔:除非他们把我们打昏了,然后再拖走.
Carrol: They will have to bashed in our heads and carry out our limp bodies.
摄影师:这样电视就会直播出来的.
Cameraman: You'll wait tell we go on live young lady.
麦琪:杰森,你就不能劝劝孩子们吗?
Maggie: Jason, will you please talk some sense into these kids?
杰森:听着,孩子们,我想这事……
Jason: Look kids, here I think that, ummm.....
麦琪:杰森,你在干吗?
Maggie: Jason, what are you doing?
杰森:我也和他们一起静坐.
Jason: I am sitting in .
学生们:喔!
Students: Yeah!!
摄影师:麦琪,注意了.
Cameraman: Stand by Maggie.
学生们:不,他不能走!不,他不能走!
Students: Heck no, he won't go.Heck no, he won't go.
麦琪:杰森?
Maggie: Jason?
杰森:对不起,亲爱的!但是……
Jason: Sorry honey but...
摄影师:五,四,三,二.
Cameraman: 5, 4,3,2...
麦琪:你们这是怎么回事?我是说这里发生了什么?
Maggie: What's the matter with you people?I mean what's going...
摄影师:开始!
Cameraman: 1!!
麦琪:我是麦琪·马龙,我现在在德文伊中学,
Maggie: This is Maggie Malone, I'm here in Dewy High School,
今天下午的早些时候这里发生了一场学生示威,目的是关于学校一教师的解聘问题.
where a protest broke
out earlier this afternoon, centering around the firing of a teacher
警察:我们不接受最后的警告,现在只能逮捕你们.
Police: You have had your final warning, you are all under arrest.
麦琪:哦,学生都被逮捕了.
Maggie: Oh, they are all under arrest.
警察:你们有权保持沉默.
Police: You have the right to remain silent.
麦琪:他们有权保持沉默.
Maggie: They have the right to remain silent.
警察:你们有权请律师为你们辩护.
麦琪:小心他们的脑袋,你们这些纳粹分子!杰瑞,下面该你了.
Police: You have the right to an attorney.... Maggie: Watch their heads you Nazis!!! Back
to you, Jerry